Just like we've been using deer and help and type on the repel, there are a few really helpful methods associated with instances and classes as well.
So we can check the type, like we've been doing, so cars.car, that's a type.
The type of my Subaru, it's the type is this class itself, right?
So just like we did with int, the type of int is a class type.
The type of an instance of int is the class itself.
There's a built in method called is instance to help us answer the question of is this particular instance of this particular type.
So this is just built in, you don't have to import it from any way.
Anywhere, I can ask, is the instance 42 of type int?
I'll get true.
Is instance of hello worlds?
Is this a string?
Yes.
Is instance 42 string?
No, it's not.
Is instance my Subaru, and int.
Nope.
If I ask is instance my Subaru cars.car, it's true, right?
We saw that earlier when we looked at the types.
Just kind of a funny interesting factoid here.
Don't use this in production code.
If I check is instance of a Boolean within, I'll see true.
So we talked about how the Boolean, the truthiness value of zero is false.
The truthiness value of any number but zero is true.
Booleans were added in Python later on after integers.
And they wanted to kind of make sure that this new language feature minimized disruption.
And so Booleans are a subclass of it.
And again, don't do this.
But you can add them together.
It's not a syntax error.
So need of this is why if you have a set and you have zero, one true false.
You actually only get zero and one back because they're duplicates.
Oops.
That's not what I wanted to do.
Don't do this in production code.
It's pretty bad.
One place you might find this a little bit useful.
This isn't in the course website just to digress a little bit.
There are two really useful methods called all and any.
So any you can pass an a list and it will say are any of these values truthy.
And this is really weird, right?
It's kind of hard to read.
I even find it hard to remember that negative one is true truthy in Python, right?
So the better way of doing this would be, you know, true true false truth.
And then you can say are any of these true.
You can also use all and ask are all of these true and you'll get false.
So anyway, interesting little fact to it.
And everything in Python is a subclass of this kind of greater built in type that we don't really use called object.
So integer strings, booleans under the head, they're all objects.